Daiei Co . , Ltd .
A Daiei / Nippon Television Network / / Hakuhodo / lmagica Production
Change course . Direction , 120 degrees .
Roger , hard to port .
Hard to port .
I need navigational information .
It all began one day ...
without warning ...
like this ...
Still no answer at Taguchi 's ?
No .
It 's been a week . He must have his reasons .
It shouldn 't take a whole week to work on that disk .
No ...
Something 's wrong .
Maybe I should see if he 's okay .
I just got the creeps .
What ?
I don 't know , I just feel like something 's wrong .
Like something 's ... horribly wrong .
What 's up with Taguchi ?
I don 't know .
If we don 't get that disk now , we 're in real trouble .
The deadline 's tomorrow .
I know that .
What am I supposed to do ? We haven 't heard a thing .
I think I 'd better go see how he 's doing .
A KUROSAWA Kiyoshi film
Taguchi ?
PULSE ( Kairo )
Hey , you are here .
Hey , Michi ...
I was worried about you . You haven 't called .
Right , sorry .
Did you finish working on that disk ?
Yeah , it 's somewhere in that pile .
You okay ? Are you sick ?
No ...
What have you been up to , all on your lonesome ? We 're friends .
Yeah ... Stuff ...
Help yourself to the disk .
You ought to label your disks .
This it ?
The one marked Work File ?
Taguchi ?
Michi .
Oh , Junco .
You okay ? Was it awful ?
I 'm fine .
I 'd say it 's break time .
Oh , I forgot . Here .
Thanks .
It 's so upsetting .
I don 't know what he was so depressed about .
He never said anything , so what could we have done ?
Maybe ...
he suddenly just wanted to die .
I get that way sometimes .
It 's so easy to hang yourself .
Hey ! Why so gloomy ?
Oh , sorry .
About Taguchi ?
It 's just ... If only I 'd ...
He seemed like the Taguchi I know .
I never imagined he 'd do something like that .
Time to put it behind us . Besides , it wasn 't your fault .
Yeah ...
Say ... Would you take a look ?
At what ?
Taguchi 's disk .
What is it ?
It 's Taguchi 's place .
Is that Taguchi ?
Yeah , I think so .
Look .
What 's going on ? Isn 't that the same scene ?
I can 't tell .
Hey , look .
That 's a face ...
A reflection .
You 're right .
Can you blow it up ?
Let me see ...
That was Taguchi , wasn 't it ?
Sure seems like it .
What 's going on ?
Maybe something strange is going on .
Strange ?
I don 't know .
I don 't even care anymore .
Something 's definitely not right .
A message in a bottle launched 10 years ago
by a boy on Tanegashima Island
was recently discovered
on a beach in Malaysia some 4,000kms away ,
Hikono Koichi was
a 4th grader when he sent off his message ,
Members of a local group , cleaning up the beach ,
a sea turtle habitat ,
discovered the bottle by accident ,
I never imagined it would find its way to some foreign country ,
I was shocked to get an answer after 10 years ,
The group located Hikono
through his former elementary school ,
Next , the National Weather Service
forecasts another unseasonably hot summer , it 's the 3rd
for eastern Japan , for western Japan ,
Northern Japan , will ,
" Welcome to the Internet . "
No , this way , here .
Okay .
Next , okay .
Next .
" Have Fun . " Okay , I 'll have fun .
Done . " Okay . "
What 's this crap ? Yes , I agree .
Next ...
What ? I guess that 's okay .
Next again , huh ?
What ?
What the ... oh , well ...
What the hell ...
Hey ... this ...
Who 's ... what 's ...
Would you like to meet a ghost ?
Stupid crap !
What the ...
Maybe you should change the size on this batch file .
Using the variable ?
Yeah .
So you 'll find its property , right ?
Oh , conventional memory .
Right .
See .
So that 's how you do it .
Say ...
Can the internet dial you up itself ?
You in computer science ?
No , economics . No relation .
Huh ... Sounds like a hacker .
A hacker ...
Huh ...
It said , " Do you want to meet a ghost ? "
Some website like that .
A ghost , huh ...
Which website was that ?
What ?
Something about meeting ghosts ?
I don 't really know . It just appeared last night .
Know the address ?
What ? Um ... address ?
I see .
Windows ?
Yeah .
Open the Explorer log ...
Oh , no , no , I really don 't know anything about computers .
The next time the site shows up ,
click on it to bookmark it .
Not so fast .
Click ...
Can you repeat that ?
Click on it .
Click ... on ... it ...
To bookmark it .
To ...
bookmark it .
If that doesn 't work ,
you know the print screen key ?
Yeah , this one ?
Try pressing it .
If it doesn 't work ...
Print screen key .
Press the ...
Print screen ...
Got it .
Let me know ?
Sure .
See you .
Don 't bother with that , Mom .
What ? Sure .
Are you eating this junk again ?
It 's not good for you .
I 'm going now .
Have you called your father ?
Nope .
I see ... but what if you get in trouble ?
I can 't rush over .
It 's awkward for me to see him , but you should .
Forget it . He 's out of the picture .
He lives here in Tokyo .
But Tokyo 's huge .
I know , but ...
I 'm fine . I 've got my friends .
You sure ? I guess you 'll be all right then .
You 're so trusting and get carried away ...
Hello .
Help ...
Who 's this ?
What is this ...
The Forbidden Room
Taguchi ?
What happened , Taguchi ...
What ?
What am I saying ?
What happened to Yabe ?
Try his house ?
No answer .
Huh ...
I hope nothing 's wrong .
Oh , no . What 's he up to ?
I 've got to go see him .
No ! Don 't go !
He 'll turn up . He 'll come if we wait !
Nothing strange has happened yet .
Yeah ...
Let 's just act normal .
Yeah , at least for today .
Sorry , I 'm late .
Sure , sure .
Where were you ? Why didn 't you call ?
Hey !
Can you believe , he 's ignoring us !
What 's going on ?
Who cares ...
What do I do now ?
Click it ...
and bookmark it .
Doesn 't work .
If that doesn 't work , press the print screen key .
There .
Hi .
You 're the one ...
Um ...
Kawashima .
Yeah , Kawashima .
I 'm Karasawa Harue .
Harue-san , Harue-san .
How 'd it go ?
Well , it came back again .
Really ?
Yeah .
And ...
I pressed that print screen key ...
Right .
Can I come over and check it out ?
Yeah , sure , absolutely fine .
I just need a minute .
Um ...
What 's this ?
That ? Something we programmed here .
If two dots get too close , they die ,
but if they get too far apart , they 're drawn closer .
Huh ... what 's it for ?
A miniature model of our world ...
But only the grad student who designed it understands it .
I wouldn 't ...
suggest staring at it for too long .
Sorry , it 's a mess .
Thank you .
There you go .
Getting the data ?
Yeah , almost set .
What got you started on the internet ?
Nothing in particular ...
You don 't like computers , right ?
No .
Wanted to connect with other people ?
Maybe ... I don 't know .
Everybody else is into it .
People don 't really connect , you know .
What ?
Like those dots simulating humans .
We all live totally separately .
That 's how it seems to me .
Oh ... Huh ...
I wonder ...
Yabe ...
Kudo-san .
Yes .
Can you move these orchids into the greenhouse ?
Um , boss ...
Yes ?
Isn 't Yabe acting strange ?
You think so ?
Can I go check on him ?
Fine , but ...
It might be a waste of time .
Words said in friendship with the best of intentions ...
always wind up hurting your friends deeply .
And then you wind up getting hurt .
Is friendship always that way ?
If that 's so , what 's left ?
If I were you ...
Who needs friends like that ?
A courageous choice in itself .
Are you okay ?
Did something happen ?
If something happened , let 's talk about it .
Both Junco and I ...
are really worried .
I saw ...
A face ...
What ?
A horrible face ...
I 've never seen anything like it ...
What are you saying ? What did you see ?
The Forbidden Room .
Forbidden Room ? What 's that ?
Is that ...
the room with the red tape ?
Don 't dare go in there !
Please ...
tell me .
What happened ?
I 'm cold .
Yabe ...
Are you okay ?
Exit
Harue .
Hi .
I don 't really use the library much .
Couldn 't find the way out .
Phantoms
You reading this ?
Yeah .
Is it related to your work in the lab ?
Huh ...
Do you have a minute ?
What ? Sure .
Come .
Isn 't it strange ?
Yeah ... sort of ...
Almost like ghosts , right ?
You 're right , they 're like ghosts .
Sometimes , these turn up .
At first , they look like the other dots .
What are they ?
I don 't know .
A bug ?
No .
That website ...
What ?
Oh , what happened with that ?
Nothing ... yet ...
Huh ...
But I think they 're related
I 'm sure they 're related .
You think ?
Let me know if anything happens .
Yeah , sure .
Karasawa-san .
I need you to check this .
Yes .
And you are ?
My friend , Kawashima .
Huh ...
The grad student , Yoshizaki-san .
Hello .
I forgot to give you my number .
Oh , right .
Call me , okay ?
Right .
Anytime , okay ?
Yeah .
Thank you .
" Everyone dies , therefore there 's no logical reason for ghosts not to exist .
" How many ghosts have ...
" existed since prehistoric times ... "
Do you see it too ?
Sure you do , because it 's really there .
Who is that ?
You 'll have to catch him to find out .
Start right now and you might succeed .
Have a go ?
What ?
Why don 't you , right now ?
He disappeared .
I see .
He must be a student ... I don 't know him .
Maybe you 're right . Sorry I encouraged you .
See you .
Wait a minute .
Just what was that ?
I 'm cold ...
The spirit ...
Or consciousness , the soul , whatever you want to call it ,
it turns out the realm they inhabit has a finite capacity .
Whether that capacity accommodates billions or trillions ...
eventually , it will run out of space .
Once it 's filled to the brim ...
it 's got to overflow somehow , somewhere .
But where ?
The souls have no choice
but to ooze into another realm , that is to say , our world .
Maybe , at first ...
it started with something really simple
Once that realm reached critical mass ...
any device would have sufficed .
Thrown it together with the means and materials at hand .
That 's how I see it .
Excuse me , do you have any tape ?
Anything 'll do , some tape .
How 's this ?
Thank you .
After many hours or days ...
or many weeks , it finally happens .
Through that process , it spread around the world .
But now they 're no longer the faint presence they began as .
You saw one yourself .
I don 't believe your stories .
Right , sorry , it 's all hypothetical .
Thanks for the tea .
Are you okay ?
Just fine .
But if this really happened ,
there 's no turning back .
No matter how simple the device ,
once the system 's complete , it 'll function on its own ...
and become permanent .
In other words ...
the passage is now open ... that 's how it looks .
Hello .
Oh , I see , our boss isn 't there ?
Yes , I understand .
If he does stop by ,
will you please ask him to call us ?
Yes , thank you very much .
Michi ...
what do you think 's going on ?
Why 's everyone disappearing ?
Oh , hello . This is Sunny Plant Sales calling .
Thank you for your business .
Is our boss there with you by any chance ?
Oh , I see ... Thank you , and excuse me .
I 'll go look for him .
Wait , Junco , wait .
Yes , hello ...
Boss ?
Help .
Yabe !
Are you Yabe ?
Help me ...
Help ...
Junco ...
Junco !
Junco , no !
Are you okay ?
Junco .
Help me ...
Junco !
Look , I 'm right here .
I 'm right here , it 's okay .
Excuse me .
Karasawa Harue tel : 090-4079-2677
What are you doing , Harue !
You 're dripping wet !
They went away ...
They 've all disappeared ... They always do ...
I have to run away ...
Run away somewhere ...
Harue !
Hey , Harue !
Listen , Harue !
Harue !
Calm down ! Harue !
Thank you ...
I always wondered what it 's like to die ...
From when I was really little ...
I was always alone .
Any parents or family ?
Sure , but they 're irrelevant .
Right ...
That after death ...
you live happily with everyone over there .
Can we stop talking about this ?
But it may be true .
Sure , but ...
Then in high school it dawned on me ...
you might be all alone after death , too .
There 's no way to know .
How could you ?
The idea was so terrifying .
I couldn 't even bear it .
That nothing changes with death ,
just right now , forever .
Is that what becoming a ghost is about ?
You can 't mess with that . It 's really bad .
What have ghosts got to do with us ?
Besides , we 're alive .
Then , who are they ?
Are they really alive ?
How are they different from ghosts ?
In fact ...
ghosts and people are the same ...
whether they 're dead or alive .
It 's not right . It 's wrong .
They 're all crazy .
Nobody knows what happens when you die .
All this about ghosts , but I won 't believe in them , even if I see one .
But I do know ...
that I 'm definitely alive and so are you , Harue .
That 's for sure , right ?
So I don 't want to think about the fact we 'll die someday .
Just maybe ...
in 10 years , or at least while we 're still alive ...
they 'll invent a drug that prevents death .
Then , we could live forever and ever .
Of course you might think I 'm crazy to say that , but ...
I 'd rather bet on that .
You want to live forever ?
Yeah .
That sounds like fun ?
Yeah ... That 's what I think .
Huh ... Maybe I 've got it all wrong .
No ...
It 'll turn out just like you say .
I 'm sure .
What ?
Ghosts won 't kill people .
Because that would just make more ghosts .
Isn 't that right ?
Instead , they 'll try to make people immortal .
By quietly ...
trapping them in their own loneliness .
Help ...
Junco , it 'll be okay .
It 'll be okay .
Okay ...
I fell asleep ...
How do you feel ?
Yeah .
Something to drink ? How about some coffee ?
Michi ...
What ?
Am I just going to die like this ?
Of course not .
That 's right ...
I 'll just keep on living , all alone ...
What ?
No .
Junco !
Junco .
Why ! Why !
Junco , don 't go !
Junco .
Mother ?
Mother !
I 'll be right there .
Harue ...
Harue ! Hey ...
Kawashima ... take me with you .
I 'm scared to be alone .
Take me somewhere .
Okay , sure .
Where to ?
Somewhere far away .
Out of Order
Shit , let 's just go !
There 's no one ...
No ...
Where did everyone go ?
I 'm here .
I 'm here beside you .
Even if ...
there 's no one else , it doesn 't matter .
We are both definitely here .
Guess that 's true ...
What happened !
I 've got to go back !
What ? No ! We 've come this far !
But this is the end of the line .
That 's not true . It 'll start moving .
I 'll go check with the driver . Come with me .
Okay , but promise you 'll wait right here .
I 'll be right back . Promise .
Harue !
The Forbidden Room
Construction Materials - red tape
I 'm ...
Not alone ...
Harue ,
it 's me , Kawashima .
Harue ! Listen !
Listen , what do you say to this ...
The two of us live together .
That way , we can always be together .
If we keep living alone ,
we 'll get worse and worse because we 're weak .
We 'll balance each other out .
How ' bout living that way ?
Would you try it with me ?
What do you think , Harue ? Listen !
Harue !
Tokyo : Missing Sakai Mitsuo
Tokyo : Missing Yamazaki Naoko
Kanagawa : Missing Hirayama Michio
Kanagawa : Missing Kawahara Takumi
Saitama : Missing Tomioka Shigeki
Tokyo : Missing Yoshida Tomoko
Tokyo : Missing Nakajima Kumi
Kanagawa : Missing Kitaoka Eri
Tokyo : Missing Fukuda Tatsuya
Um ... are you okay ?
Breakdown ?
Yeah .
Want some ?
You are ?
Oh , me ? Um ...
What are you doing here ?
What am I doing here ...
You ?
So neither your dad nor your mum ...
made it through ...
No ...
So many things happened at once ...
it 's impossible to sort them all out .
Yeah .
Me too . My head 's all messed up .
So you 're a student , Kawashima ?
Yeah .
Lucky you .
I don 't think so .
Here .
Oh , thanks ...
And you ?
I had a job .
Wow , amazing .
Nothing amazing .
Did you have any friends ?
Friends ?
Maybe one , I guess .
What was she like ?
What ? I don 't really know ...
I never really found out ...
Where is she ?
Somewhere ...
Okay , try starting it .
Okay , good .
Why don 't you look for her ?
What ?
She 's still somewhere , right ? You 've got to help her then .
But ...
Let 's go find her . I 'll help you .
This is the last stop ...
After that we go as far as we can .
I can sort of see ...
The future ...
Help Help Help Help Help
Look over there .
An abandoned factory ?
I wonder ...
Shall we try it ?
Listen , even if you see a door sealed with red tape ,
don 't go near it , okay ?
I know .
You okay ?
Look ... at this .
Look ... over there .
Kawashima .
Harue !
Watch out !
What happened , Harue !
What are you doing with that ?
Let 's get out of this place together .
Together ?
Yeah .
C 'mon , hand it over .
Harue ! Harue !
Oh , no , a hospital ...
Harue ! Don 't die !
C 'mon ! Please !
Help me !
Harue !
We couldn 't save her ...
No ...
We 're out of gas ...
I 'll get some , there was gas back there .
You 'll be okay ?
Wait for me . I 'll be okay .
Forever ...
Death was ...
Eternal loneliness ...
Help .
Don 't ask me ! What 's that got to do with me !
Forever ...
Death was ...
Eternal loneliness ...
You 're not real .
I refuse to acknowledge ... Never ...
I refuse to acknowledge death !
I know .
I 'll catch you .
Then you 'll disappear .
That 's it , right ! Right !
You can 't beat me !
I am ...
Real ...
Kawashima !
What is it ?
Forget it ... Let 's go ...
It 's too much ...
What ... are you doing ?
You went in there ...
Me ?
Yeah , I did , but I 'm fine .
Don 't cry .
You want to go back ?
To what 's left of Harue ?
That make you feel better ?
If that 's what you want , I 'll go with you .
No ...
Let 's go ...
As far as we can go .
Are you sure about that ?
Yeah .
Can you get out ?
You okay ?
Be careful .
Wait here , okay ?
Death comes to us all ...
If so , maybe we would 've been happier
if we had gone with the rest .
But we chose to keep going ...
into the future ...
We 'll head for Latin America .
We 're still getting signals there .
Though they 're pretty weak .
We 've got to give it a try ...
no matter what we find .
If anyone 's survived ...
we can head out again ...
and go as far as we can .
C 'mon , be strong .
Have I done the right thing ?
Yes .
Are you sure ?
You 're doing the right thing .
Now , alone with my last friend in the world ...
I have found happiness .
CAST
Kawashima : KATO Haruhiko
Michi : ASO Kumiko
Harue : KO YUKI
Junco : ARISAKA Kurume Yabe : MATSUO Masatoshi
The Boss : SUGATA Shun Taguchi : MIZUHASHI Kenji
The Ghost : SHIONOYA Masayuki
The Worker : AIKAWA Show
Michi 's mother : FUBUKI Jun
Yoshizaki : TAKEDA Shinji
The Captain : YAKUSHO Koji
Executive Producer : TOKUMA Yasuyoshi
Producers : SHIMIZU Shun OKUDA Seiji
Producers : INOUE Ken SHIMODA Atsuyuki
Director of Photography : HAYASHI Junichiro
Lighting Director : TOMIYAMA Meicho
Production Designer : MARUO Tomoyuki
Sound : IKA Makio
Editor : KIKUCHI Junichi
Music Producer : WADA Toru Composer : HAKETA Takefumi
Theme Song by : Cocco " Wings ~ lay down my arms ~ "
Visual Effects : ASANO Shuji
Written and Directed by : KUROSAWA Kiyoshi